<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="show_messages_check">Show messages?</string>
    <string name="simulate_bluetooth_check">Simulate Bluetooth?</string>
    <string name="view_message_title_string">Title:</string>
    <string name="view_message_data_string">Message:</string>
    <string name="language_text">Language:</string>
    <string name="message_text">Message:</string>
    <string name="title_text">Title</string>
    <string name="app_name">Fluid Nexus</string>
    <string name="settings_title">Settings (Fluid Nexus)</string>
    <string name="message_view_title">View Message (Fluid Nexus)</string>
    <string name="help_title">Help + About (Fluid Nexus)</string>
    <string name="message_add_outgoing_title">New Message (Fluid Nexus)</string>
    <string name="message_edit_title">Edit Message (Fluid Nexus)</string>
    <string name="message_view_outgoing_title">View Outgoing Messages (Fluid Nexus)</string>
    <string name="message_list_header_text_all">ALL MESSAGES</string>
    <string name="message_list_header_text_public">PUBLIC MESSAGES</string>
    <string name="message_list_header_text_outgoing">OUTGOING MESSAGES</string>
    <string name="message_list_header_text_blacklist">BLACKLISTED MESSAGES</string>
    <string name="menu_message_list_context_title">Context menu</string>
    <string name="menu_add_message">New Message</string>
    <string name="menu_view_all">View All</string>
    <string name="menu_view_public">View Public</string>
    <string name="menu_view_outgoing">View Outgoing</string>
    <string name="menu_view_blacklist">View Blacklist</string>
    <string name="menu_delete">Delete Message</string>
    <string name="menu_blacklist">Blacklist Message</string>
    <string name="menu_unblacklist">Unblacklist Message</string>
    <string name="menu_edit">Edit Message</string>
    <string name="menu_preferences">Preferences</string>
    <string name="menu_request_authorization">Request Nexus Authorization</string>
    <string name="menu_help">Help + About</string>
    <string name="really_delete_dialog">Are you sure you want to delete this message?</string>
    <string name="really_blacklist_dialog">Are you sure you want to blacklist this message?</string>
    <string name="really_unblacklist_dialog">Are you sure you want to remove this message from the blacklist?</string>
    <string name="no_key_dialog">No Nexus Key or Nexus Secret exists.  These are necessary in order to request authorization.  Please visit http://fluidnexus.net and create an account (or login to an existing one) and request a Nexus Key and Secret.  If you already have a Key and Secret, please enter them into the Preferences.</string>
    <string name="really_save_dialog">Do you want to save this message?</string>
    <string name="same_dialog">The message you are trying to save already exists in the database; please change the title and/or the content.</string>
    <string name="view_message_back">Back</string>
    <string name="save_message_button">Save</string>
    <string name="discard_message_button">Discard</string>
    <string name="open_attachment_button_text">Open</string>
    <string name="title_edit_label">Title:</string>
    <string name="message_edit_label">Message:</string>
    <string name="public_label">Public (push to nexus)?</string>
    <string name="attachment_add_label">Attachment:</string>
    <string name="add_attachment_prompt">Attachment Type</string>
    <string name="add_attachment_button">Add Attachment...</string>
    <string name="remove_attachment_button">Remove Attachment...</string>
    <string name="settings_save_button">Save</string>
    <string name="settings_cancel_button">Cancel</string>
    <string name="button_help">Help</string>
    <string name="button_concept">Concept</string>
    <string name="button_return">Return</string>
    <string name="notification">Fluid Nexus Notification</string>
    <string name="notification_bluetooth">Fluid Nexus Bluetooth Notification</string>
    <string name="notification_title_new_message">New Message</string>
    <string name="notification_fluid_nexus_device_found">Fluid Nexus device found</string>
    <string name="notification_fluid_nexus_discovery_complete">Device discovery complete</string>
    <string name="notification_fluid_nexus_services_complete">Services discovery complete</string>
    <string name="notification_fluid_nexus_send_outgoing_complete">Sending outgoing message</string>
    <string name="toast_bluetooth_settings_changed">Bluetooth simulator       settings changed; please restart the emulator and Fluid Nexus.  If using the bridge, be sure it is running before you start Fluid Nexus in the emulator.</string>
    <string name="toast_bluetooth_server_simulator_complete">This is the end of the Bluetooth server (receive) simulator.  If you want to see the messages being added again, please restart the emulator.</string>
    <string name="toast_new_message_received">New message received.</string>
    <string name="toast_message_deleted">Message deleted.</string>
    <string name="toast_message_blacklisted">Message blacklisted.</string>
    <string name="toast_message_unblacklisted">Message unblacklisted.</string>
    <string name="intent_new_message">net.fluidnexus.FluidNexus.NEW_MESSAGE</string>
    <string name="intent_discovery_started">net.fluidnexus.FluidNexus.DISCOVERY_STARTED</string>
    <string name="intent_device_found">net.fluidnexus.FluidNexus.REMOTE_DEVICE_FOUND</string>
    <string name="intent_discovery_completed">net.fluidnexus.FluidNexus.DISCOVERY_COMPLETED</string>
    <string name="intent_service_discovery_completed">net.fluidnexus.FluidNexus.SERVICE_DISCOVERY_COMPLETED</string>
    <string name="intent_send_messages_completed">net.fluidnexus.FluidNexus.SEND_MESSAGES_COMPLETED</string>
    <string name="service_started">Fluid Nexus service started</string>
    <string name="service_stopped">Fluid Nexus service stopped</string>
    <string name="service_label">Fluid Nexus Network service</string>
    <string name="preferences">Fluid Nexus Preferences</string>
    <string name="preferences_category_interface">Interface</string>
    <string name="preferences_category_network">Network</string>
    <string name="preferences_category_bluetooth">Bluetooth</string>
    <string name="preferences_category_zeroconf">Zeroconf</string>
    <string name="preferences_category_nexus">Nexus</string>
    <string name="preferences_show_messages">Show messages?</string>
    <string name="preferences_show_messages_summary">Whether or not to show messages in the interface.</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_bluetooth_service">Bluetooth Service</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_bluetooth_service_summary">Whether or not the bluetooth service is enabled.  This service will run even when the application has ended.</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_zeroconf_service">Zeroconf Service</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_zeroconf_service_summary">Whether or not the zeroconf service is enabled.  This service will run even when the application has ended.  This feature is under development.</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_adhocwifi_service">Ad-Hoc Wifi Service</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_adhocwifi_service_summary">Whether or not the Ad-Hoc Wifi service is enabled.  This service will run even when the application has ended.  This feature is under development.</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_nexus_service">Nexus Service</string>
    <string name="preferences_enable_nexus_service_summary">Whether or not the application tries to post public messages to the Nexus.  This feature requires some sort of access to the internet over Wifi, but will still run without problems if Wifi is not enabled</string>

    <string name="preferences_bluetooth_scan_frequency">Scan Frequency</string>
    <string name="preferences_bluetooth_scan_frequency_summary">How often to scan for other devices.  Shorter durations will severely impact battery life.</string>
    <string name="preferences_zeroconf_scan_frequency">Scan Frequency</string>
    <string name="preferences_zeroconf_scan_frequency_summary">How often to scan for other devices.  Shorter durations will severely impact battery life.</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_key">Nexus Key</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_key_summary">The key provided by to you on the Fluid Nexus website for posting to the Nexus</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_key_title">Nexus Key</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_secret">Nexus Secret</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_secret_summary">The secret provided by to you on the Fluid Nexus website for posting to the Nexus</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_secret_title">Nexus Secret</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_token">Nexus Token </string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_token_summary">The token provided by to you on the Fluid Nexus website for posting to the Nexus.  This should not need to be changed, but is rather added automatically upon pressing "Request authorization token" in the main menu.</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_token_title">Nexus Token</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_token_secret">Nexus Token Secret</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_token_secret_summary">The token secret provided by to you on the Fluid Nexus website for posting to the Nexus.  This should not need to be changed, but is rather added automatically upon pressing "Request authorization token" in the main menu.</string>
    <string name="preferences_nexus_token_secret_title">Nexus Token Secret</string>
    <string name="toast_tokens_updated">Tokens updated; application is now authorized to post to the Nexus.</string>

    <string name="help_help_text">There are two types of messages in Fluid Nexus.  The first, \"outgoing\", are messages you have created and that are designed to be the first ones sent to other nearby phones.  These are indicated by the icon with the arrow pointing  left, outside of the device.  The second are messages that you have received from other phones; these are indicated by the icon without the arrow.  Your phone will try and send these messages after it has sent all of the messages marked as outgoing.\n
\n
VIEWING A MESSAGE: Simply click/tap/hit enter on a message to open a window that allows you to see the entirety of the message.\n
DELETING A MESSAGE: Once you have selected a message using the keyboard or direction pad, open the menu and select \"Delete message\" to remove it from the database and advertisements.\n
ADDING A MESSAGE: Open the menu and select \"New Message\".  Enter your message, select save, and it will be queued for for sending, as well as appearing in your message list.\n
VIEW ALL MESSAGES: The default opening view of Fluid Nexus, this shows all of the messages on your device.  You can also return to this view by opening the menu and selecting \"View All\".\n
VIEW OUTGOING: This shows you only the messages you have created and that are thus marked as \"outgoing\".  You can select this by opening the menu and selecting \"View Outgoing\".\n
\n
ABOUT\n
\n
Google Android port by Nick Knouf.\n
\n
Nokia Series 60 Python version by Nick Knouf with Bruno Vianna, Luis Ayuso, and Mónica Sánchez.\n
\n
Source code is available from http://fluidnexus.net and is licensed under the GPLv3.  Code is available at <a href="https://github.com/zeitkunst/FluidNexusAndroid">https://github.com/zeitkunst/FluidNexusAndroid</a> and for the desktop version <a href="https://github.com/zeitkunst/FluidNexus">https://github.com/zeitkunst/FluidNexus</a>.</string>
    <string name="help_concept_text">Fluid Nexus is an application for mobile phones that is primarily designed to enable activists or relief workers to send messages and data amongst themselves independent of a centralized cellular network.  The idea is to provide a means of communication between people when the centralized network has been shut down, either by the government during a time of unrest, or by nature due to a massive disaster.  During such times the use of the centralized network for voice or SMS is not possible.  Yet, if we can use the fact that people still must move about the world, then we can use ideas from sneaker-nets to turn people into carriers of data.  Given enough people, we can create fluid, temporary, ad-hoc networks that pass messages one person at a time, spreading out as a contagion and eventually reaching members of the group.  This enables surreptitious communication via daily activity and relies on a fluid view of reality.  Additionally, Fluid Nexus can be used as a hyperlocal message board, loosely attached to physical locations.\n
\n
Fluid Nexus is not designed as a general-purpose piece of software; rather, it is developed with specific types of users in mind.  Thus, while the ideas here could be very useful for social-networking or productivity applications, this is not what I am most interested in.  However, I definitely welcome the extension of these ideas into these other domains.  Indeed, Fluid Nexus is related to work in the following projects: mesh networking in the OLPC ( http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Mesh_Network_Details ), the Haggle project ( http://www.haggleproject.org/ ), and Comm.unity ( http://community.mit.edu/ ), among many others.\n
\n
BLUETOOTH SIMULATION: For the purposes of this competition, I have simulated Bluetooth connections since the emulator does not at present support Bluetooth natively.  There are two different types of simulation.  The first is a purely software version that fires Bluetooth events for both the client and the server.  The second is a bridge that sits outside of the emulator and connects, over a forwarded TCP socket, the emulator to the host Bluetooth adapter.  This bridge is written in python using the lightblue (http://lightblue.sourceforge.net ) library.  For the competition I show notifications for all device and service discovery, as well as for sending outgoing messages; in an actual application, these notifications would not be shown.\n
\n
MESSAGE FORWARDING: Right now we only implement broadcast-style forwarding; future versions will allow the creation of pre-defined groups for more limited distribution.  The forwarding algorithm works by reappropriating the advertisement of Bluetooth services to advertise hashes of already-received messages.  This is similar to what many insects do in the wild, by leaving traces of prior activity in an area, known as stigmergy.  Thus messages leave traces of where they\'ve been, via the advertisement of their hashes, thus greatly increasing the efficiency of this broadcast-style forwarding algorithm.  For more information, please see the PDF documentation available online ( http://fluidnexus.net/media/pdf/FluidNexusAndroid.pdf ).
    </string>

    <string name="ro_perm_label">read messages</string>
    <string name="ro_perm_desc">Allows applications to read messages from the Fluid Nexus content provider.</string>
    <string name="wo_perm_label">write messages</string>
    <string name="wo_perm_desc">Allows applications to write messages to the Fluid Nexus content provider.</string>
    <string name="network_perm_label">start network service</string>
    <string name="network_perm_desc">Allows applications to start the network service via intent.</string>

    <string name="bt_perm_label">start bluetooth service</string>
    <string name="bt_perm_desc">Allows applications to start bluetooth service via intent.</string>
    <string name="zeroconf_perm_label">start zerconf service</string>
    <string name="zeroconf_perm_desc">Allows applications to start zeroconf service via intent.</string>

</resources>
